[
    {
        "front": "うんどうします|||",
        "back": "(take) exercise",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "せいこうします|||",
        "back": "succeed",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "しっぱいします|||*\n［しけんに～］",
        "back": "fail [an examination]",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "ごうがくします|||\n［しけんに～］",
        "back": "pass [an examination]",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "やみます|||\n［あめが～］",
        "back": "[rain] stop",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "はれます||",
        "back": "clear up",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "くもります| ",
        "back": "get cloudy",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "つづきます|\n［ねつが～］ ",
        "back": "[high temperature/fever] continue ",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "ひきます|\n［かぜを～］ ",
        "back": "catch [a cold]",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "ひやします| ",
        "back": "cool",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "こみます|\n［みちが～］",
        "back": "[a road] get crowded",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "すきます|\n［みちが～］",
        "back": "[a road] get less crowded",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "でます||\n［しあいに～］\n［パーティーに～］",
        "back": "participate [in the match]; attend [a party]",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "よりを　します|||",
        "back": "overdo things",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "じゅうぶん［な］　 ",
        "back": "enough, sufficient",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "おかしい ",
        "back": "strange, funny",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "うるさい ",
        "back": "noisy",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "せんせい",
        "back": "doctor",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "やけど ",
        "back": "burning (～を　します: get burned)",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "けが ",
        "back": "injury (～を　します: get injured)",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "せき ",
        "back": "cough (～を　します/～が　でます: have a cough)",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "インフルエンザ",
        "back": "influenza",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "そら ",
        "back": "sky",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "たいよう* ",
        "back": "sun",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "ほし ",
        "back": "star",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "かぜ ",
        "back": "wind",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "ひがし*",
        "back": "east",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "にし ",
        "back": "west",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "みなみ",
        "back": "south",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "きた*",
        "back": "north",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "こくさい～",
        "back": "international~",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "すいどう ",
        "back": "faucet, tap, water supply",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "エンジン ",
        "back": "engine",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "チーム ",
        "back": "team",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "こんや ",
        "back": "this evening",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "ゆうがた ",
        "back": "late afternoon",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "まえ ",
        "back": "a time in the past, before",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "おそく ",
        "back": "late (time)",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "こんなに*",
        "back": "this (much, etc.) ",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "そんなに* ",
        "back": "that (much, etc.)  (concerning a matter related to the listener)",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "あんなに ",
        "back": "that (much, etc.) (concerning a matter not related to the speaker or the listener)",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "※ヨーロッパ",
        "back": "Europe",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "げんき",
        "back": "vigour",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "い",
        "back": "stomach",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "ストレス",
        "back": "stress",
        "chapter": 32
    },
    {
        "front": "それは　いけませんね",
        "back": "I'm sorry to hear that",
        "chapter": 32
    }
]